Guide to the Cannery Workers and Farm Laborers Union Local 7 Records
Special Collections, University of Washington Libraries
- CANNERY WORKERS AND FARM LABORERS' UNION, LOCAL 7 (UNITED CANNERY, AGRICULTURAL, PACKING & ALLIED WORKERS OF AMERICA-CIO), 1933-1952; 1981-1982; RECORD GROUP 3 (Box-folder 10/1-23/28)
  - General Records, 1936-1944; Subgroup A (Box-folder 10/1-21/34)
    - BUTTON--CWFLU #7, 1939; SERIES XXXV (Box-folder 19/8)
    - NOTES, Undated; SERIES XXXVI (Box-folder 19/9)
    - PHOTOGRAPHS--Crew, 1940-1941; SERIES XXXVII (Box-folder 19/10-19/15)
      - Pacific American Fisheries--Alitak Cannery, 1941 (Box-folder 19/10)
      - San Juan Fish Packaging Co.--Uganik-San Juan Cannery, 1940 (Box-folder 19/11)
      - Kadiak Fisheries Co.--Port Bailey Cannery, 1940 (Box-folder 19/12)
      - Libby, McNeill & Libby--Kenai Cannery, 1941 (Box-folder 19/13)
      - Wards Cove Packaging Co.--Wards Cove Ketchikan Cannery, 1940 (Box-folder 19/14)
      - Libby, McNeill & Libby--Yakutat Cannery, 1940 (Box-folder 19/15)
    - PHOTOGRAPHS, 1944; SERIES XXXVIII (Box-folder 19/16-19/17)
      - Abella Case (originally from "claims"), 1944 (Box-folder 19/16)
      - Unidentified, Undated (Box-folder 19/17)
    - PAYROLL RECORDS, 1937; SERIES IXXXX (Box-folder 19/18)
    - CLIPPINGS, 1938-1939; SERIES XXXX (Box-folder 19/19)
    - BULLETINS--Union, 1936-1939; SERIES XXXXI (Box-folder 19/20)
    - MAILINGS, 1937-1942; SERIES XXXXII (Box-folder 19/21)
    - BLANK FORMS--miscellaneous, Undated; SERIES XXXXIII (Box-folder 19/22)
      - BLANK FORMS-miscellaneous, 1938-1943
      - Miscellaneous, 1938-1943 (Box-folder 19/23)
      - Cannery Food Supplies, Undated (Box-folder 19/24)
      - Costs and Pack Values, c. 1940 (Box-folder 19/25)
    - LISTS, 1938-1940; SERIES XXXXIV
    - ARTWORK, Undated; SERIES XXXXV (Box-folder 19/26)
  - Budget Committee, 1941-1942; Subgroup A (Box-folder 19/27)
  - California Delegation, 1939-1940; Subgroup B (Box-folder 19/27)
  - Cooks Committee, 1940; Subgroup C (Box-folder 19/29)
  - Delegates Committee, 1939-1941, Undated; Subgroup D (Box-folder 19/30-19/34)
    - Minutes, Reports, Lists & Misc., 1939-1941 (Box-folder 19/30)
    - Applications, Undated (Box-folder 19/31-32)
    - Questionnaires, Undated (Box-folder 19/33)
    - Blank Questionnaires, Undated (Box-folder 19/34)
  - Committee on Disciplinary Rules, 1938; Subgroup E (Box-folder 19/35)
  - Educational Committee, 1940; Subgroup F (Box-folder 19/36)
  - Foremen's Qualifying Committee, 1937-1941; Subgroup G (Box-folder 19/37-19/50)
    - Letters of Complaint, 1937 (Box-folder 19/37)
    - Applications, 1938-1941 (Box-folder 19/38-19/41)
    - Lists of foremen and foremen applicants, 1938 (Box-folder 19/42)
    - Minutes and Rules, 1938, 1940 (Box-folder 19/43-19/44)
    - Foremen's Conference, 1939 (Box-folder 19/45)
    - Recommendations for foremen applicants, 1940 (Box-folder 19/46)
    - Letters re: Foremen positions, 1940 (Box-folder 19/47)
    - Notes, 1940 (Box-folder 19/48)
    - Memorandum, 1941 (Box-folder 19/49)
    - Miscellaneous, 1938 (Box-folder 19/50)
  - Grievance Committee, 1937, Undated; Subgroup H (Box-folder 19/51-19/52)
    - Claims for extra pay, 1937 (Box-folder 19/51)
    - Grievances of members & employers, 1937, Undated (Box-folder 19/52)
  - Investigation Committee, 1937-1940; Subgroup I (Box-folder 19/53-19/65)
    - Series I: Complaints Regarding Foremen Delegates, 1937-1938 (Box-folder 19/53)
    - Series II: Delegates' Reports, 1939 (Box-folder 19/54-19/61)
      - Libby, McNeill & Libby, 1939 (Box-folder 19/54)
      - Nakat Packing Company, 1939 (Box-folder 19/55)
      - Alaska Pacific Salmon Co., 1939 (Box-folder 19/56)
      - Pacific American Fisheries, Inc., 1939 (Box-folder 19/57)
      - P.E. Harris Company, 1939 (Box-folder 19/58)
      - Copper River Packaging Co./San Juan Fish Packaging Co., 1939 (Box-folder 19/59)
      - Pioneer Seafoods/Hood Bay; Kadiak/Sebastian Stuart/Emard/Alaska Red Salmon/ Peril Straights, 1939 (Box-folder 19/60)
      - New England Fish Co./Alaska Southern Packaging Co., 1939 (Box-folder 19/61)
    - Series III: Summons, 1940 (Box-folder 19/62)
    - Series IV: Miscellaney, 1938-1940 (Box-folder 19/63-19/65)
  - Political Welfare Committee, 1938-1939; Subgroup J (Box-folder 20/1)
  - Relief Committee, 1937-1938, Undated; Subgroup K (Box-folder 20/2-20/3)
  - Special Committee Studying Conditions of #7, 1939-1940; Subgroup L (Box-folder 20/4)
  - Strategy Committee, 1938; Subgroup M (Box-folder 20/5)
  - Farm Division, 1937-1941; Subgroup N (Box-folder 20/6-20/20)
    - GENERAL RECORDS, 1937-1941; SERIES I (Box-folder 20/6-20/13)
      - General Correspondence, 1938-1940 (Box-folder 20/6)
      - Minutes, 1938-1940 (Box-folder 20/7)
      - Petitions & Authorizations, 1940 (Box-folder 20/8)
      - Membership Records, 1937-1938 (Box-folder 20/9)
      - Agreements Bainbridge Island, 1938-1940 (Box-folder 20/10)
      - General Correspondence, 1937-1941 (Box-folder 20/11)
      - Agreement & Petitions, 1937-1941 (Box-folder 20/12)
      - Authorizations & Lists, 1937-1941 (Box-folder 20/13)
    - AUBURN-KENT AREA, 1941, Undated; SERIES II (Box-folder 20/14-20/18)
      - Outgoing Letters, 1941 (Box-folder 20/14)
      - Notes, Undated (Box-folder 20/15)
      - Minutes & Lists, 1941 (Box-folder 20/16)
      - Agreements, 1941 (Box-folder 20/17)
      - Membership applications & cards--postal receipts, 1941 (Box-folder 20/18)
    - KENT, ORILLA, O'BRIEN & VICINITY, Undated; SERIES III (Box-folder 20/19)
      - Petition, Undated (Box-folder 20/19)
    - PUYALLUP AREA (SUMNER), 1940; SERIES IV (Box-folder 20/20)
      - Incoming Letters, 1940 (Box-folder 20/20)
  - UCAPAWA, Local #1--Yakima Valley, 1937-1938; Subgroup O (Box-folder 20/21-20/22)
    - General Correspondence--Mostly Harry V. Olson, Sec. Dist. 1 UCAPAWA, 1937-1938 (Box-folder 20/21)
    - Minutes, Lists, Financial, Contracts, 1937 (Box-folder 20/22)
  - Port Althorp, 1939; Subgroup P (Box-folder 20/23)
    - Minutes, 1939 (Box-folder 20/23)
  - UCAPAWA, International Represenative/Business Agent, Subgroup Q
    - GENERAL CORRESPONDENCE, 1943-1944; SERIES I (Box-folder 20/24-20/29)
      - UCAPAWA, 1943-1944 (Box-folder 20/24-26)
      - UCAPAWA--Donald Henderson, 1943 (Box-folder 20/27)
      - UCAPAWA--Dixie Tiller, 1943 (Box-folder 20/28)
      - UCAPAWA--Legislative & Research Department, 1943-1944 (Box-folder 20/29)
    - GENERAL CORRESPONDENCE--LOCAL & BRANCHES, 1943-1944; SERIES II (Box-folder 20/30-20/37)
      - Local #5, San Francisco, 1943-1944 (Box-folder 20/30)
      - Local #7, False Pass, Alaska, 1943- 1944 (Box-folder 20/31)
      - Local # 7-2, Seattle, 1943 (Box-folder 20/32)
      - Local #222, Petersburg, Alaska, 1943 (Box-folder 20/33)
      - Local # 226, Portland, 1943 (Box-folder 20/34)
      - Local #237, Ketchikan, Alaska, 1943 (Box-folder 20/35)
      - Local # 263, Hoonah, Alaska, 1943-1944 (Box-folder 20/36)
      - Local # 269, Juneau, Alaska, 1943 (Box-folder 20/37)
    - GENERAL CORRESPONDENCE, 1939-1944; SERIES III (Box-folder 20/38-20/46)
      - Alaska Delegates, 1943 (Box-folder 20/38)
      - Rose Delama-- S.E. Alaska Cannery Workers, 1943-1944 (Box-folder 20/39)
      - Anthony Dimond--Delegate, Territory of Alaska, 1943 (Box-folder 20/40)
      - Personal Correspondence of A.E. Harding, 1943 (Box-folder 20/41)
      - U.S. National War Labor Board, 1943- 1944 (Box-folder 20/42)
      - U.S. O.P.A. For Additional Gas Allowance, 1943-1944 (Box-folder 20/43)
      - U.S. War Manpower Commission, 1943 (Box-folder 20/44)
      - Van Griffin and Gershon, Attorneys, 1939-1943 (Box-folder 20/45)
      - Miscellaneous Correspondence, 1940-1943 (Box-folder 20/46)
    - GENERAL CORRESPONDENCE--REGARDING: BLACKLISTING, 1943-1944; SERIES IV (Box-folder 20/47-20/53)
      - Pacific American Fisheries, Inc., 1943-1944 (Box-folder 20/47)
      - Emard Packing Co., 1944 (Box-folder 20/48)
      - New England Fish Co., 1943-1944 (Box-folder 20/49)
      - Red Salmon Canning Co., 1943 (Box-folder 20/50)
      - Kadiak Fisheries, Inc., 1943 (Box-folder 20/51)
      - Parks Canning Co., 1943-1944 (Box-folder 20/52)
      - Peninsula Packing Company, 1943 (Box-folder 20/53)
    - GENERAL CORRESPONDENCE RE:, 1942-1944; SERIES V (Box-folder 20/54-20/66)
      - Men Justifiably Fired, 1943 (Box-folder 20/54)
      - Back-Door Maneuvering, 1942-1943 (Box-folder 20/55)
      - Bristol Bay Jurisdictional Dispute, 1944 (Box-folder 20/56)
      - Bristol Bay Resident Workers, 1943-1944 (Box-folder 20/57)
      - Chignik Residents, 1944 (Box-folder 20/58)
      - Clearance of Workers With War Department For, 1943-1944 (Box-folder 20/59)
      - Copper River Case on Overtime Claim for Painting, 1943-1944 (Box-folder 20/60-61)
      - Exemptions from Executive Order 9240, 1943 (Box-folder 20/62)
      - Jobs Through Other Unions, 1943 (Box-folder 20/63)
      - Oregon Fruit & Vegetable Canneries, 1943 (Box-folder 20/64)
      - Provisions For Electing Harding Business Agent, 1943 (Box-folder 20/65)
      - Racial Discrimination, 1943 (Box-folder 20/66)
  - UCAPAWA. International Representative--(Steve Glumaz), Subgroup R
- CANNERY WORKERS' AND FARM LABORERS' UNION. LOCAL 7. (FOOD, TOBACCO, AGRICULTURAL AND ALLIED WORKERS UNION OF AMERICA-CIO), 1933-1949; RECORD GROUP 4 (Box-folder 21/35-26/13)
  In their original state, most of the files could not be identified as those of a single officer. They included records primarily of the union's secretary, in mixture with correspondence of the president, other officers and other records. There were, however, some segments, which were distinct files accumulated by a single individual. These papers have been kept intact as subgroups within the appropriate chronological division. In Record Group 4, there are subgroups for the Regional Director/International Organizers Robert Kinney and Wendal Phillips and the Oregon State Director/International Organizer, Frank T. Patterson. These men were not elected officials but worked for the union. The papers in their subgroups were separately and uniformly labeled files.
  - General Records, 1933-1950; Subgroup A (Box-folder 21/35-24/86)
  - FTA. Regional Director/International Organizer (Robert Kinney, Wendal Phillips), 1946-1950; Subgroup B (Box-folder 25/1-25/22)
  - FTA. Oregon State Director/International Organizer (Frank T. Patterson), 1944-1949; Subgroup C (Box-folder 25/23-26/2)
  - Election Committee, 1945, 1947; Subgroup D (Box-folder 26/3-26/5)
  - Election Investigation Committee, 1949; Subgroup E (Box-folder 26/6)
  - Emergency Committee, 1947; Subgroup F (Box-folder 26/7)
  - Foremens Meetings, 1946; Subgroup G (Box-folder 26/8)
  - Grievance Committee, 1945(?)-1947; Subgroup H (Box-folder 26/9-10)
  - Organizing Committee, 1947; Subgroup I (Box-folder 26/11)
  - Rank and File Committee, 1947-1948; Subgroup J (Box-folder 26/12)
  - Trial Committee, 1949; Subgroup K (Box-folder 26/13)
- INTERNATIONAL LONGSHOREMEN'S & WAREHOUSEMEN'S UNION, LOCAL 37, 1943-1987; RECORD GROUP 5 (Box-folder 26/14-33/57)
  - General Records, Subgroup A
  - Committe for Justice for Domingo and Viernes, 1981-1984; Subgroup B (Box-folder 33/19)
  - ILWU. Local 37. Fact Finding Committee, 1954; Subgroup C (Box-folder 33/20)
  - ILWU. Local 37. Rank and File Committee, 1975-1982; Subgroup D (Box-folder 33/21-33/56)
  - Valdez, Gregorio A., 1952-1954; Subgroup E (Box-folder 33/57)
- EXTERNAL ORGANIZATIONS AND PERSONAL PAPERS, 1915-1979; RECORD GROUP 6 (Box-folder 33/58-37/12)
  Subgroups were created reflecting the union's participation in various external organizations, such as the Maritime Federation of the Pacific, various CIO bodies, and Filipino organizations.
  - Cannery and Agricultural Workers Benevolent Association, 1937; Subgroup A (Box-folder 33/58-33/59)
  - Filipino Community of Seattle, 1952-1959; Subgroup B (Box-folder 33/60)
  - Filipino Unemployed Cititzen’s League (Filipino Community Welfare League), 1933; Subgroup C (Box-folder 33/61)
  - Maritime Federation of the Pacific, 1936-1941; Subgroup D (Box-folder 33/62-34/20)
  - Pacific Coast Fisheries Organization and Coordinating Committee, 1937-1939; Subgroup E (Box-folder 34/21-34/30)
  - Seattle Industrial Labor Union Council (Seattle CIO Council), 1937-1948; Subgroup F (Box-folder 34/31-34/51)
  - Washington Commonwealth Federation, 1938-1948; Subgroup G (Box-folder 34/52-34/59)
  - Washington State Industrial Union Council (Washington CIO), 1938-1950; Subgroup H (Box-folder 34/60-35/13)
  - Velasco, Victorio Personal Papers, 1928-1968; Subgroup I (Box-folder 35/14-35/29)
    A small subgroup was created for papers of Victoria Velasco which were found in various places throughout the records. These papers primarily reflect Velasco's involvement with other unions and a small amount related to non-union activities.
  - Viernes, Gene Personal Papers, 1937-1980; Subgroup J (Box-folder 35/30-37/12)
    - Part 1 General Files (Box-folder 35/30-36/47)
      - HISTORICAL FEATURES - “BRIEF HISTORY OF LOCAL SEVEN (FTA-CIO)”, 1950; SERIES I (Box-folder 35/30)
      - ORGANIZATIONAL FEATURES - CWFLU # 7 AND ILWU # 37, 1953-1979; SERIES II (Box-folder 35/31-35/34)
      - INTRA-ORGANIZATIONAL CORRESPONDENCE - ILWU # 37, SERIES III (Box-folder 37/2)
      - OUTGOING LETTERS OF:, 1947-1978; SERIES IV (Box-folder 35/35-35/36)
      - GENERAL CORRESPONDENCE, 1947-1974; SERIES V (Box-folder 35/37-35/39)
      - REPORTS, 1915-1977; SERIES VI (Box-folder 35/40-35/42)
      - SPEECHES AND WRITINGS, 1937-1977, Undated; SERIES VII (Box-folder 35/43-35/48)
      - CONTRACTS, 1973-1979; SERIES VIII (Box-folder 35/49-35/53)
      - LEGAL PAPERS - NATIONAL LABOR RELATIONS BOARD CASES, 1948, 1978; SERIES IX (Box-folder 35/54)
      - COURT PAPERS, 1947-194; SERIES X (Box-folder 35/55)
      - FINANCIAL RECORDS, 1946-1970; SERIES XI (Box-folder 35/56)
      - TRANSCRIPTS, 1936-1939; SERIES XII (Box-folder 35/57-36/1)
      - FORMS, Undated; SERIES XIII (Box-folder 36/1)
      - LISTS, 1942-1976, Undated; SERIES XIV (Box-folder 36/2-36/3)
      - PETITION, 1977, Undated; SERIES XV (Box-folder 36/4-36/5)
      - PROGRAMS AND ANNOUNCEMENTS, 1952, Undated; SERIES XVI (Box-folder 36/6)
      - PAMPHLETS, 1948; SERIES XVII (Box-folder 36/8)
      - PUBLICATIONS, 1971-1977; SERIES XVIII (Box-folder 36/9-36/11)
      - PHOTOGRAPHS, 1973, Undated; SERIES IXX (Box-folder 36/12-36/13)
      - NOTES - ILWU # 37, 1968; SERIES XX (Box-folder 36/14)
      - EPHEMERA, 1952-1979; SERIES XXI (Box-folder 36/15)
      - NEWSLETTERS, 1922-1979; SERIES XXII (Box-folder 36/16-36/31; Oversize VF36)
      - CLIPPINGS, 1929-1980; SERIES XXIII (Box-folder 36/32-36/47)
      - PROCESSING NOTES, Undated; SERIES XXIV (Box-folder 36/47)
    - Part 2 Alaska Cannery Workers Association
- MISCELLANEOUS SERIES, RECORD GROUP 7 (Box-folder 38-53; Oversized VF 36)
  - PHOTOGRAPHS (Box-folder 38 & Oversized VF 36)
  - DISPATCHING, CREW LISTS, MEMBERSHIP AND FINANCIAL RECORDS (Unsorted), ca.1930s-1980 (Box-folder 39-53)